# **David Cheng**

# Senior Full Stack Developer

#### Texas City, TX, United States

♠ david.chengup@gmail.com





\ +1(601)975-2620 in linkedin.com/in/david-cheng-a07296355/

## **SUMMARY**

As a senior software developer with more than 8 years experiences, I am responsible for building Full Stack Solutions from scratch for a lot of industries including E-learning platforms, Satellite communication, Healthcare and Finance. For example, the global healthcare industry that I have participated was valued at around \$12 billion in 2023 and is projected to reach \$ 20 billion by 2030. I am sure that I will delivery successful result in any kind of industry that you are planning to improve and move forwards.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Full Stack Developer/Rust

Sunny Isles, FL, US

Hivex | Aug 2023 - Dec 2024

- Developed custom Linux kernel modules using Rust to enhance system performance and safety in user-space and kernel-space interactions.
- Built a secure sandboxing tool in **Rust** leveraging seccomp and namespaces to isolate untrusted processes with minimal overhead.
- Created a **CLI tool** in Rust to monitor real-time system resource usage (CPU, memory, I/O), with custom alerts and reporting.
- Contributed to open-source Rust crates focused on Linux system APIs (nix, libc), improving documentation and patching minor bugs.
- Refactored existing Linux shell scripts into Rust binaries for enhanced execution speed and reliability.
- Integrated multi-threading and asynchronous operations (tokio, async-std) to handle parallel monitoring and system I/O.
- Developed a Rust-based CLI tool to monitor system load, running processes, disk usage, and generate daily reports in JSON and CSV formats.

The Software House | May 2022 – Jun 2023

- Developed E-Learning website for children, Wellness & Fitness website, Food Delivery & Ride Ordering Platform with **React**, **Next.js** as frontend and **Django** with **Python** as backend.
- Suggested robust and scalable backend solutions, ensuring high performance and security that optimized API response times by 60%, resulting in a smoother user experience.
- Advanced efficient payment processing workflows with **Stripe**, reducing transaction processing time by 40%, which resulted in a 25% increase in successful payments and a 15% boost in user satisfaction.
- Utilized project management tools such as **Jira** and **Trello** to streamline workflows and enhance project visibility.
- Launched OAuth authentication and two-factor authentication (2FA) to enhance user security and streamline login processes, ensuring the protection of user data.
- Proceeded code reviews, offering valuable feedback to enhance code quality and maintain coding standards using GitLab and Bitbucket.
- Executed the design of robust **CI/CD pipelines**, leveraging **Jenkins**, **Docker**, and **Kubernetes**, resulting in a significant reduction in software development and release cycles.

# **Software Engineer | Microservice**

London, England

Pixelette Technology | Jan 2021 - Apr 2022

- Collaborated in the design and implementation of **CI/CD** and **DevOps** processes for agile projects, accelerating deployment frequency by 70% and reducing production errors by 40%.
- Worked with technologies and platforms such as Python, Java, Javascript, Git, Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Ngnix, Jenkins, AWS, used debugging tools like React-DevTools for faster debugging and reducing debugging time by 50%.
- Experienced on **TDD**, followed test-first methodology in refactoring projects, wrote unit and integration tests using **Jest**, **Mocha**, and **Cypress**, and test coverage was more than 80%.
- Implemented best practices in microservices architecture, enhancing scalability to handle a 200% increase in user traffic and boosting overall performance by reducing response times by 50%.
- Leveraged cloud services such as AWS, GCP, and DigitalOcean to deploy, scale, and manage
  infrastructure, reducing infrastructure costs by 35% and improving deployment speed by
  60%, while maintaining 99.99% system uptime.

### Stockholm, Sweden

## Middle Web Developer

OpenGeeksLab | Jan 2020 - Dec 2020

- Refactored event management and appointment management system for company internal members by migrating from HTML to Angular.
- Maintained a large web application using HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP
   (Laravel) framework, and automated monthly supplier payments billing cycle using
   PHP and MySQL. Ran payment programs on a monthly basis and adjusted
   conditional business logic through a web interface.
- Turned mockups and designs into actual responsive websites and sliced or extracted the PSDs myself when asked, and finished responsive 3-5 pages in less than 72 hours, given specific time frames ranging from 3 to 5 days.
- Contributed to the successful delivery of projects on time and within budget, consistently meeting or exceeding client expectations.

# **EDUCATION**

Aug 2015 – Dec 2019 University of North Texas
Bachelor's Degree, Computer science

TX, US

#### **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Rust, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Python, PHP, C#, Golang, Java
- Frontend: React.js, Next.js, Angular 2, Vue.js, Redux, Hooks, React Query, MUI, JQuery, BS5, Tailwind
- Backend: Python, Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, .NET, .NET Core, ASP.NET, Django, Flask, FastAPI,
   Laravel, GraphQL
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, MariaDB, Azure SQL, SQL server
- Cloud and DevOps: Amazon web services(AWS), Azure DevOps services, Google cloud platform,
   Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD pipelines